A wrist control that we can use from a slashing attack.
We're going to do it from the outside.
We want to create a protective barrier once again.
Create a diversionary framework. A Danny comes in here I want to follow that motion. Trap on top of the wrist right here and as he begins to pull back to get into position I want to follow him once again.
A technique we have seen several times before.
Because it's exceptionally effective.
Which is why we're seeing it again.
Here I create my protective line.
I'm off the line of attack.
The blade's far enough away from me that if it misses it misses.
I'm here.
And then I control the hand.
He wants to bring it back naturally.
I'll flow with him.
We don't want to get into a wrestling match.
I don't want to fight him down here to keep it here.
He want to bring it up?
That's fine.
I'll go right with him.
Boom.
We want to control the motion and use his energy against him as much as possible.
This motion is nice and small in an ever shrinking circle going gently past his forearm down into the ground.
I don't want to heave him 40 yards away.
I want him on the ground at my feet as quickly as possible.
Here and down we go to the ground.
And that is a good wrist control from a slashing attack.